<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-johnstone-johnstone.xml</filename>
    <author>Abraham Johnstone</author>
    <title>The Address of Abraham Johnstone, a Black Man, Who Was Hanged at Woodbury, in the County
      of Glocester, and State of New Jersey, on Saturday the the [sic] 8th Day of July Last; to the
      People of Colour. To Which Is Added His Dying Confession or Declaration. Also, a Copy of a
      Letter to His Wife, Written the Day Previous to His Execution</title>
    <date>1797</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-meachum-meachum.xml</filename>
    <author>John B. Meachum</author>
    <title>An Address to All the Colored Citizens of the United States</title>
    <date>1846</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-johnsontl-johnsontl.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas L. Johnson</author>
    <title>Africa for Christ. Twenty-Eight Years a Slave</title>
    <date>1892</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-white-white.xml</filename>
    <author>William S. White</author>
    <title>The African Preacher. An Authentic Narrative</title>
    <date>1849</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brown55-brown55.xml</filename>
    <author>William Wells Brown</author>
    <title>The American Fugitive in Europe. Sketches of Places and People Abroad</title>
    <date>1855</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-weld-weld.xml</filename>
    <author>Theodore Dwight Weld</author>
    <title>American Slavery As It Is: Testimony of a Thousand Witnesses</title>
    <date>1839</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-andersrob-andersrob.xml</filename>
    <author>Robert Anderson</author>
    <title>The Anderson Surpriser. Written After He Was Seventy-Five Years of Age. The Author Was
      Born in Liberty County, Ga., on the 22d Day of February, in the Year of Our Lord, 1819, and
      United with the Methodist Episcopal Church in the Year 1839. This Book Contains an Account of
      His Florida and Northern Trip, Written by Himself, Giving Much Valuable Information of the
      People Among Whom He Had Been Several Months</title>
    <date>1895</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-boen-boen.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>Anecdotes and Memoirs of William Boen, a Coloured Man, Who Lived and Died Near Mount
      Holly, New Jersey. To which is Added, the Testimony of Friends of Mount Holly Monthly Meeting
      Concerning Him</title>
    <date> 1834</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-stevens-stevens.xml</filename>
    <author>Charles Emery Stevens</author>
    <title>Anthony Burns: A History</title>
    <date>1856</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-robinsonn-robinson.xml</filename>
    <author>Nina Hill Robinson</author>
    <title>Aunt Dice: The Story of a Faithful Slave</title>
    <date>1897</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-auntjudy-auntjudy.xml</filename>
    <author>Matilda G. Thompson</author>
    <title>Aunt Judy&apos;s Story: A Tale From Real Life. Written for the Pennsylvania Anti-Slavery
      Fair</title>
    <date>1855</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-sally-sally.xml</filename>
    <author>Isaac Williams</author>
    <title>Aunt Sally: or, The Cross the Way of Freedom. A Narrative of the Slave-life and Purchase
      of the Mother of Rev. Isaac Williams of Detroit, Michigan</title>
    <date>1858</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jamison-jamison.xml</filename>
    <author>M. F. Jamison</author>
    <title>Autobiography and Work of Bishop M. F. Jamison, D.D. (&quot;Uncle Joe&quot;) Editor,
      Publisher, and Church Extension Secretary; a Narration of His Whole Career from the Cradle to
      the Bishopric of the Colored M. E. Church in America</title>
    <date> 1912</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-wards-ward.xml</filename>
    <author>Samuel Ringgold Ward</author>
    <title>Autobiography of a Fugitive Negro: His Anti-Slavery Labours in the United States, Canada,
      &amp;amp; England</title>
    <date>1855</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-lane-lane.xml</filename>
    <author>Isaac Lane</author>
    <title>Autobiography of Bishop Isaac Lane, LL.D. with a Short History of the C.M.E. Church in
      America and of Methodism</title>
    <date>1916</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-parkerh-parkerh.xml</filename>
    <author>Henry Parker</author>
    <title>Autobiography of Henry Parker</title>
    <date>1865</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-smithj-smithj.xml</filename>
    <author>James Lindsay Smith</author>
    <title>Autobiography of James L. Smith, Including, Also, Reminiscences of Slave Life,
      Recollections of the War, Education of Freedmen, Causes of the Exodus, etc.</title>
    <date>1881</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-said-said.xml</filename>
    <author>Nicholas Said</author>
    <title>The Autobiography of Nicholas Said, A Native of Bournou, Eastern Soudan, Central
      Africa</title>
    <date>1873</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>nc-omarsaid-omarsaid.xml</filename>
    <author>Omar ibn Said</author>
    <title>Autobiography of Omar ibn Said, Slave in North Carolina, 1831. Ed. John Franklin Jameson.
      From The American Historical Review, 30, No. 4. (July 1925), 787-795</title>
    <date>1925</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-frederick-frederick.xml</filename>
    <author>Francis Frederick</author>
    <title>Autobiography of Rev. Francis Frederick, of Virginia</title>
    <date>1869</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-henry-henry.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas W. Henry</author>
    <title>Autobiography of Rev. Thomas W. Henry, of the A. M. E. Church</title>
    <date>1872</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-henson81-henson81.xml</filename>
    <author>Josiah Henson</author>
    <title>An Autobiography of the Rev. Josiah Henson (&quot;Uncle Tom&quot;). From 1789 to 1881.
      With a Preface by Mrs. Harriet Beecher Stowe, and Introductory Notes by George Sturge, S.
      Morley, Esq., M. P., Wendell Phillips, and John G. Whittier. Edited by John Lobb, F.R.G.S.
      Revised and Enlarged</title>
    <date>1881</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-holsey-holsey.xml</filename>
    <author>Lucius Henry Holsey</author>
    <title>Autobiography, Sermons, Addresses, and Essays of Bishop L. H. Holsey, D. D.</title>
    <date> 1898</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-washstory-washin.xml</filename>
    <author>Booker T. Washington</author>
    <title>An Autobiography: The Story of My Life and Work</title>
    <date>1901</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-smitham-smith.xml</filename>
    <author>Amanda Smith</author>
    <title>An Autobiography: The Story of the Lord&apos;s Dealings with Mrs. Amanda Smith, the
      Colored Evangelist: Containing an Account of Her Life Work of Faith, and Her Travels in
      America, England, Ireland, Scotland, India, and Africa as an Independent Missionary</title>
    <date>1893</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-campbell-campbell.xml</filename>
    <author>Israel Campbell</author>
    <title>An Autobiography. Bond and Free: Or, Yearnings for Freedom, from My Green Brier House.
      Being the Story of My Life in Bondage, and My Life in Freedom</title>
    <date>1861</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-alexander-alexander.xml</filename>
    <author>Charles Alexander</author>
    <title>Battles and Victories of Allen Allensworth, A. M., Ph. D., Lieutenant-Colonel, Retired,
      U. S. Army</title>
    <date>1914</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-aleckson-aleckson.xml</filename>
    <author>Sam Aleckson</author>
    <title>Before the War, and After the Union. An Autobiography</title>
    <date>1929</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-keckley-keckley.xml</filename>
    <author>Elizabeth Keckley</author>
    <title>Behind the Scenes, or, Thirty years a Slave, and Four Years in the White House</title>
    <date>1868</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-carolinatwin-carolinatwin.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>Biographical Sketch of Millie Christine, the Carolina Twin, Surnamed the Two-Headed
      Nightingale and the Eighth Wonder of the World</title>
    <date>1902</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-mott26-mott26.xml</filename>
    <author>Abigail Mott</author>
    <title>Biographical Sketches and Interesting Anecdotes of Persons of Colour. To Which is Added,
      a Selection of Pieces in Poetry</title>
    <date>1826</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-thompsch-thompsch.xml</filename>
    <author>Charles Thompson</author>
    <title>Biography of a Slave; Being the Experiences of Rev. Charles Thompson, a Preacher of the
      United Brethren Church, While a Slave in the South. Together with Startling Occurrences
      Incidental to Slave Life</title>
    <date>1875</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brownj-brownj.xml</filename>
    <author>Josephine Brown</author>
    <title>Biography of an American Bondman, by His Daughter</title>
    <date>1856</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-taylor-taylor.xml</filename>
    <author>James B. Taylor</author>
    <title>Biography of Elder Lott Cary, Late Missionary to Africa. With an Appendix on the Subject
      of Colonization, by J.H.B. Latrobe</title>
    <date>1837</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-ferrill-ferrill.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>Biography of London Ferrill, Pastor of the First Baptist Church of Colored Persons,
      Lexington, KY</title>
    <date>1854</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-baquaqua-baquaqua.xml</filename>
    <author>Mahommah Gardo Baquaqua</author>
    <title>Biography of Mahommah G. Baquaqua, a Native of Zoogoo, in the Interior of Africa. (A
      Convert to Christianity,) With a Description of That Part of the World; Including the Manners
      and Customs of the Inhabitants, Their Religious Notions, Form of Government, Laws, Appearance
      of the Country, Buildings, Agriculture, Manufactures, Shepherds and Herdsmen, Domestic
      Animals, Marriage Ceremonials, Funeral Services, Styles of Dress, Trade and Commerce, Modes of
      Warfare, System of Slavery, &amp;amp;c., &amp;amp;c. Mahommah&apos;s Early Life, His
      Education, His Capture and Slavery in Western Africa and Brazil, His Escape to the United
      States, from Thence to Hayti, (the City of Port Au Prince,) His Reception by the Baptist
      Missionary There, The Rev. W. L. Judd; His Conversion to Christianity, Baptism, and Return to
      This Country, His Views, Objects and Aim. Written and Revised from His Own Words, by Samuel
      Moore, Esq., Late Publisher of the &quot;North of England Shipping Gazette,&quot; Author of
      Several Popular Works, and Editor of Sundry Reform Papers</title>
    <date>1854</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-dsmith-dsmith.xml</filename>
    <author>David Smith</author>
    <title>Biography of Rev. David Smith of the A. M. E. Church; Being a Complete History, Embracing
      over Sixty Years&apos; Labor in the Advancement of the Redeemer&apos;s Kingdom on Earth.
      Including &quot;The History of the Origin and Development of Wilberforce
      University.&quot;</title>
    <date> 1881</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brownww-brown.xml</filename>
    <author>William Wells Brown</author>
    <title>The Black Man: His Antecedents, His Genius, and His Achievements</title>
    <date>1863</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brinch-brinch.xml</filename>
    <author>Boyrereau Brinch</author>
    <title>The Blind African Slave, or Memoirs of Boyrereau Brinch, Nick-named Jeffrey Brace.
      Containing an Account of the Kingdom of Bow-Woo, in the Interior of Africa; with the Climate
      and Natural Productions, Laws, and Customs Peculiar to That Place. With an Account of His
      Captivity, Sufferings, Sales, Travels, Emancipation, Conversion to the Christian Religion,
      Knowledge of the Scriptures, &amp;amp;c. Interspersed with Strictures on Slavery, Speculative
      Observations on the Qualities of Human Nature, with Quotation from Scripture</title>
    <date>1810</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-blair-blair.xml</filename>
    <author>Norvel Blair</author>
    <title>Book for the People! To Be Read by All Voters, Black and White, with Thrilling Events of
      the Life of Norvel Blair, of Grundy County, State of Illinois. Written and Published by Him,
      and with the Money He Earned by His Own Labor, and Is Sent Out with the Sincere Hope that if
      Carefully Read, It Will Tend to Put a Stop to Northern Bull-Dozing and Will Give to All a Free
      Ballot, without Fear, Favor or Affection and Respect</title>
    <date>1880</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-scott-scott.xml</filename>
    <author>Emmett J. Scott</author>
    <title>Booker T. Washington, Builder of a Civilization</title>
    <date>1916</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-whitegeo-whitegeo.xml</filename>
    <author>George White</author>
    <title>A Brief Account of the Life, Experience, Travels, and Gospel Labours of George White, an
      African; Written by Himself, and Revised by a Friend</title>
    <date>1810</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-ferebee-ferebee.xml</filename>
    <author>L. R. Ferebee</author>
    <title>A Brief History of the Slave Life of Rev. L. R. Ferebee, and the Battles of Life, and
      Four Years of His Ministerial Life. Written from Memory. To 1882</title>
    <date>1882</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-tilmon-tilmon.xml</filename>
    <author>Levin Tilmon</author>
    <title>A Brief Miscellaneous Narrative of the More Early Part of the Life of L. Tilmon: Pastor
      of a Colored Methodist Congregational Church in the City of New York</title>
    <date>1853</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-nicholson-nicholson.xml</filename>
    <author>Alfred W. Nicholson</author>
    <title>Brief Sketch of the Life and Labors of Rev. Alexander Bettis. Also an Account of the
      Founding and Development of the Bettis Academy</title>
    <date>1913</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-gaines-gaines.xml</filename>
    <author>William Walker</author>
    <title>Buried Alive (Behind Prison Walls) for a Quarter of a Century: Life of William
      Walker</title>
    <date>1892</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-lester-lester.xml</filename>
    <author>Peter Wheeler</author>
    <title>Chains and Freedom: Or, The Life and Adventures of Peter Wheeler, a Colored Man Yet
      Living. A Slave in Chains, a Sailor on the Deep, and a Sinner at the Cross</title>
    <date>1839</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-flipper-flipper.xml</filename>
    <author>Henry Ossian Flipper</author>
    <title>The Colored Cadet at West Point. Autobiography of Lieut. Henry Ossian Flipper, U. S. A.,
      First Graduate of Color from the U. S. Military Academy</title>
    <date> 1878</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jennings-jennings.xml</filename>
    <author>Paul Jennings</author>
    <title>A Colored Man&apos;s Reminiscences of James Madison</title>
    <date>1865</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-nell-nell.xml</filename>
    <author>William Cooper Nell</author>
    <title>The Colored Patriots of the American Revolution: With Sketches of Several Distinguished
      Colored Persons: To Which is Added a Brief Survey of the Condition and Prospects of Colored
      Americans</title>
    <date>1855</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-joyce-joyce.xml</filename>
    <author>John Joyce</author>
    <title>Confession of John Joyce, Alias Davis, Who Was Executed on Monday, the 14th of March,
      1808. For the Murder of Mrs. Sarah Cross; With an Address to the Public and People of Colour.
      Together with the Substance of the Trial, and the Address of Chief Justice Tilghman, on His
      Condemnation. Confession of Peter Mathias, Alias Matthews, Who Was Executed on Monday, the
      14th of March, 1808. For the Murder of Mrs. Sarah Cross; With an Address to the Public and
      People of Colour. Together with the Substance of the Trial, and the Address of Chief Justice
      Tilghman, on His Condemnation</title>
    <date>1808</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-turner-turner.xml</filename>
    <author>Nat Turner</author>
    <title>The Confessions of Nat Turner, the Leader of the Late Insurrection in Southampton,
      Va.</title>
    <date>1831</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-fjones-jones.xml</filename>
    <author>Friday Jones</author>
    <title>Days of Bondage. Autobiography of Friday Jones. Being a Brief Narrative of His Trials and
      Tribulations in Slavery</title>
    <date> 1883</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-pomp-pomp.xml</filename>
    <author> Pomp</author>
    <title>Dying Confession of Pomp, A Negro Man, Who Was Executed at Ipswich, on the 6th August,
      1795, for Murdering Capt. Charles Furbush, of Andover, Taken from the Mouth of the Prisoner,
      and Penned by Jonathan Plummer, Jun.</title>
    <date>1795</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-arter-arter.xml</filename>
    <author>Jared Maurice Arter</author>
    <title>Echoes from a Pioneer Life</title>
    <date>1922</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-eliza2-eliza2.xml</filename>
    <author> Elizabeth</author>
    <title>Elizabeth, a Colored Minister of the Gospel Born in Slavery</title>
    <date> 1889</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jonestom-jones.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas H. Jones</author>
    <title>Experience and Personal Narrative of Uncle Tom Jones; Who Was for Forty Years a Slave.
      Also the Surprising Adventures of Wild Tom, of the Island Retreat, a Fugitive Negro from South
      Carolina</title>
    <date>1855</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-jackson-jackson.xml</filename>
    <author>John Andrew Jackson</author>
    <title>The Experience of a Slave in South Carolina</title>
    <date>1862</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>nc-jones85-jones85.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas H. Jones</author>
    <title>The Experience of Rev. Thomas H. Jones, Who Was a Slave for Forty-Three Years. Written by
      a Friend, as Related to Him by Brother Jones</title>
    <date>1885</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-jones-jones.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas H. Jones</author>
    <title>The Experience of Thomas H. Jones, who was a Slave for Forty-Three Years</title>
    <date>1862</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-kelley-kelley.xml</filename>
    <author>Edmond Kelley</author>
    <title>A Family Redeemed from Bondage; Being Rev. Edmond Kelley, (the Author,) His Wife, and
      Four Children</title>
    <date>1851</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-vale-vale.xml</filename>
    <author>G. Vale</author>
    <title>Fanaticism; Its Source and Influence, Illustrated by the Simple Narrative of Isabella, in
      the Case of Matthias, Mr. and Mrs. B. Folger, Mr. Pierson, Mr. Mills, Catherine, Isabella,
      &amp;amp;c. &amp;amp;c. A Reply to W. L. Stone, with the Descriptive Portraits of All the
      Parties, While at Sing-Sing and at Third Street. - Containing the Whole Truth - and Nothing
      but the Truth</title>
    <date>1835</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-fields-fields.xml</filename>
    <author>Fields Cook</author>
    <title>Fields&apos;s Observations: The Slave Narrative of a Nineteenth-Century Virginian. From
      The Virginia Magazine of History and Biography. Vol. 88, 75-93</title>
    <date>1847</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-ball-ball.xml</filename>
    <author>Charles Ball</author>
    <title>Fifty Years in Chains, or, The Life of an American Slave</title>
    <date>1859</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-smithhar-smithhar.xml</filename>
    <author>Harry Smith</author>
    <title>Fifty Years of Slavery in the United States of America</title>
    <date>1891</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-doug1906-doug1906.xml</filename>
    <author>Booker T. Washington</author>
    <title>Frederick Douglass</title>
    <date>1906</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-chesnutt-chesnutt.xml</filename>
    <author>Charles Waddell Chesnutt</author>
    <title>Frederick Douglass</title>
    <date>1899</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-holland-holland.xml</filename>
    <author>Frederic May Holland</author>
    <title>Frederick Douglass The Colored Orator</title>
    <date>1895</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-gregory-gregory.xml</filename>
    <author>James M. Gregory</author>
    <title>Frederick Douglass The Orator. Containing an Account of His Life; His Eminent Public
      Services; His Brilliant Career as Orator; Selections from His Speeches and Writings</title>
    <date>1893</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-parker1-parker.xml</filename>
    <author>William Parker</author>
    <title>The Freedman&apos;s Story: In Two Parts</title>
    <date>1851</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-merritt-merritt.xml</filename>
    <author>Raleigh H. Merritt</author>
    <title>From Captivity to Fame or The Life of George Washington Carver</title>
    <date>1929</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-robinson-robinson.xml</filename>
    <author>William H. Robinson</author>
    <title>From Log Cabin to the Pulpit, or, Fifteen Years in Slavery</title>
    <date>1913</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-randolph-randolph.xml</filename>
    <author>Peter Randolph</author>
    <title>From Slave Cabin to the Pulpit. The Autobiography of Rev. Peter Randolph: the Southern
      Question Illustrated and Sketches of Slave Life</title>
    <date>1893</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-edwardsc-edwards.xml</filename>
    <author>S. J. Celestine Edwards</author>
    <title>From Slavery to a Bishopric, or, The Life of Bishop Walter Hawkins of the British
      Methodist Episcopal Church Canada</title>
    <date> 1891</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-heard-heard.xml</filename>
    <author>William H. Heard</author>
    <title>From Slavery to the Bishopric in the A.M.E. Church. An Autobiography</title>
    <date>1928</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-rudd-rudd.xml</filename>
    <author>Dan. A. Rudd</author>
    <title>From Slavery to Wealth. The Life of Scott Bond. The Rewards of Honesty, Industry, Economy
      and Perseverance</title>
    <date>1917</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-delaney-delaney.xml</filename>
    <author>Lucy A. Delaney</author>
    <title>From the Darkness Cometh the Light or Struggles for Freedom</title>
    <date>1891</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-penning49-penning49.xml</filename>
    <author>James W. C. Pennington</author>
    <title>The Fugitive Blacksmith; or, Events in the History of James W. C. Pennington, Pastor of a
      Presbyterian Church, New York, Formerly a Slave in the State of Maryland, United
      States</title>
    <date>1849</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-barrett-barrett.xml</filename>
    <author>Philip Barrett</author>
    <title>Gilbert Hunt, the City Blacksmith</title>
    <date> 1859</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-adamsh-adamsh.xml</filename>
    <author>H. G. Adams</author>
    <title>God&apos;s Image in Ebony: Being a Series of Biographical Sketches, Facts, Anecdotes,
      etc., Demonstrative of the Mental Powers and Intellectual Capacities of the Negro Race</title>
    <date>1854</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-troy-troy.xml</filename>
    <author>William Troy</author>
    <title>Hair-breadth Escapes from Slavery to Freedom</title>
    <date>1861</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-harriet-harriet.xml</filename>
    <author>Sarah H. Bradford</author>
    <title>Harriet, the Moses of Her People</title>
    <date>1886</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-prince-prince.xml</filename>
    <author>Mary Prince</author>
    <title>The History of Mary Prince, a West Indian Slave. Related by Herself. With a Supplement by
      the Editor. To Which Is Added, the Narrative of Asa-Asa, a Captured African</title>
    <date>1831</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-latta-latta.xml</filename>
    <author>M. L. Latta</author>
    <title>The History of My Life and Work. Autobiography by Rev. M. L. Latta, A.M., D.D.</title>
    <date>1903</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-barber-barber.xml</filename>
    <author>John Warner Barber</author>
    <title>A History of the Amistad Captives: Being a Circumstantial Account of the Capture of the
      Spanish Schooner Amistad, by the Africans on Board; Their Voyage, and Capture Near Long
      Island, New York; with Biographical Sketches of Each of the Surviving Africans; Also, an
      Account of the Trials had on Their case, Before the District and Circuit Courts of the United
      States, for the District of Connecticut</title>
    <date> 1840</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-millie-christine-millie-christine.xml</filename>
    <author>Millie-Christine</author>
    <title>The History of the Carolina Twins: Told in &quot;Their Own Peculiar Way&quot; By
      &quot;One of Them&quot;</title>
    <date>1851</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-webb-webb.xml</filename>
    <author>William Webb</author>
    <title>The History of William Webb, Composed by Himself</title>
    <date>1873</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brownhal-brownhal.xml</filename>
    <author>Hallie Q. Brown</author>
    <title>Homespun Heroines and Other Women of Distinction</title>
    <date>1926</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-simpson-simpson.xml</filename>
    <author>John Hawkins Simpson</author>
    <title>Horrors of the Virginian Slave Trade and of the Slave-Rearing Plantations. The True Story
      of Dinah, an Escaped Virginian Slave, Now in London, on Whose Body Are Eleven Scars Left by
      Tortures Which Were Inflicted by Her Master, Her Own Father. Together with Extracts from the
      Laws of Virginia, Showing That Against These Barbarities the Law Gives Not the Smallest
      Protection to the Slave, But the Reverse</title>
    <date>1863</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-albert-albert.xml</filename>
    <author>Octavia V. Rogers Albert</author>
    <title>The House of Bondage, or, Charlotte Brooks and Other Slaves, Original and Life Like, As
      They Appeared in Their Old Plantation and City Slave Life; Together with Pen-Pictures of the
      Peculiar Institution, with Sights and Insights into Their New Relations as Freedmen, Freemen,
      and Citizens</title>
    <date>1890</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-aga-aga.xml</filename>
    <author>Selim Aga</author>
    <title>Incidents Connected with the Life of Selim Aga, a Native of Central Africa</title>
    <date>1846</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-jacobs-jacobs.xml</filename>
    <author>Harriet A. Jacobs</author>
    <title>Incidents in the Life of a Slave Girl. Written by Herself</title>
    <date>1861</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-anderson-anderson.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas Anderson</author>
    <title>Interesting Account of Thomas Anderson, a Slave, Taken from His Own Lips. Ed. J. P.
      Clark</title>
    <date>1854</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-equiano1-equiano1.xml</filename>
    <author>Olaudah Equiano</author>
    <title>The Interesting Narrative of the Life of Olaudah Equiano, or Gustavus Vassa, the African.
      Written by Himself. Vol. I.</title>
    <date>1789</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-equiano2-equiano2.xml</filename>
    <author>Olaudah Equiano</author>
    <title>The Interesting Narrative of the Life of Olaudah Equiano, or Gustavus Vassa, the African.
      Written by Himself. Vol. II.</title>
    <date>1789</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>church-hatcher-hatcher.xml</filename>
    <author>William E. Hatcher</author>
    <title>John Jasper: The Unmatched Negro Philosopher and Preacher</title>
    <date>1908</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-bleby-bleby.xml</filename>
    <author>Henry Bleby</author>
    <title>Josiah: The Maimed Fugitive. A True Tale</title>
    <date>1873</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-pickard-pickard.xml</filename>
    <author>Kate E. R. Pickard</author>
    <title>The Kidnapped and the Ransomed. Recollections of Peter Still and His Wife
      &quot;Vina,&quot; after Forty Years of Slavery.</title>
    <date> 1856</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-webster-webster.xml</filename>
    <author>Pharaoh Jackson Chesney</author>
    <title>Last of the Pioneers: Or, Old Times in East Tenn., Being the Life and Reminiscences of
      Pharaoh Jackson Chesney (Aged 120 Years)</title>
    <date>1902</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-fortis-fortis.xml</filename>
    <author>Edmund Fortis</author>
    <title>The Last Words and Dying Speech of Edmund Fortis, a Negro Man, Who Appeared to Be between
      Thirty and Forty Years of Age, but Very Ignorant. He Was Executed at Dresden, on Kennebeck
      River, on Thursday the Twenty-Fifth Day of September, 1794, for a Rape and Murder, Committed
      on the Body of Pamela Tilton, a Young Girl of about Fourteen Years of Age, Daughter of Mr.
      Tilton of Vassalborough, in the County of Lincoln</title>
    <date>1795</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-sancho1-sancho1.xml</filename>
    <author>Ignatius Sancho</author>
    <title>Letters of the Late Ignatius Sancho, An African. In Two Volumes. To Which Are Prefixed,
      Memoirs of His Life. Vol. I</title>
    <date>1782</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-sancho2-sancho2.xml</filename>
    <author>Ignatius Sancho</author>
    <title>Letters of the Late Ignatius Sancho, An African. In Two Volumes. To Which Are Prefixed,
      Memoirs of His Life. Vol. II</title>
    <date>1782</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-williams-williams.xml</filename>
    <author>James Williams</author>
    <title>Life and Adventures of James Williams, a Fugitive Slave, with a Full Description of the
      Underground Railroad</title>
    <date>1873</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-natlove-natlove.xml</filename>
    <author>Nat Love</author>
    <title>Life and Adventures of Nat Love, Better Known in the Cattle Country as &quot;Deadwood
      Dick,&quot; by Himself; a True History of Slavery Days, Life on the Great Cattle Ranges and on
      the Plains of the &quot;Wild and Woolly&quot; West, Based on Facts, and Personal Experiences
      of the Author</title>
    <date> 1907</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-robert-robert.xml</filename>
    <author>Robert Voorhis</author>
    <title>Life and Adventures of Robert, the Hermit of Massachusetts: Who Has Lived 14 Years in a
      Cave, Secluded from Human Society: Comprising, an Account of his Birth, Parentage, Sufferings,
      and Providential Escape from Unjust and Cruel Bondage in Early Life, and His Reasons for
      Becoming a Recluse</title>
    <date>1829</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-marrs-marrs.xml</filename>
    <author>Elijah P. Marrs</author>
    <title>Life and History of the Rev. Elijah P. Marrs, First Pastor of Beargrass Baptist Church,
      and Author</title>
    <date>1885</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-oneal-oneal.xml</filename>
    <author>William O&apos;Neal</author>
    <title>Life and History of William O&apos;Neal, or, The Man Who Sold His Wife</title>
    <date> 1896</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-early-early.xml</filename>
    <author>Sarah J. W. Early</author>
    <title>Life and Labors of Rev. Jordan W. Early, One of the Pioneers of African Methodism in the
      West and South</title>
    <date>1894</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-andersonw-andersonw.xml</filename>
    <author>William J. Anderson</author>
    <title>Life and Narrative of William J. Anderson, Twenty-four Years a Slave; Sold Eight Times!
      In Jail Sixty Times!! Whipped Three Hundred Times!!! or The Dark Deeds of American Slavery
      Revealed. Containing Scriptural Views of the Origin of the Black and of the White Man. Also, a
      Simple and Easy Plan to Abolish Slavery in the United States. Together with an Account of the
      Services of Colored Men in the Revolutionary War--Day and Date, and Interesting Facts</title>
    <date>1857</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jjoseph-jjoseph.xml</filename>
    <author>John Joseph</author>
    <title>The Life and Sufferings of John Joseph, a Native of Ashantee, in Western Africa: Who Was
      Stolen from His Parents at the Age of 3 Years, and Sold to Mr. Johnstone, a Cotton Planter, in
      New Orleans, South America</title>
    <date>1848</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-black-black.xml</filename>
    <author>Leonard Black</author>
    <title>The Life and Sufferings of Leonard Black, a Fugitive from Slavery. Written by
      Himself</title>
    <date>1847</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-dougl92-dougl92.xml</filename>
    <author>Frederick Douglass</author>
    <title>Life and Times of Frederick Douglass, Written by Himself. His Early Life as a Slave, His
      Escape from Bondage, and His Complete History to the Present Time, Including His Connection
      with the Anti-slavery Movement; His Labors in Great Britain as Well as in His Own Country; His
      Experience in the Conduct of an Influential Newspaper; His Connection with the Underground
      Railroad; His Relations with John Brown and the Harpers Ferry Raid; His Recruiting the 54th
      and 55th Mass. Colored Regiments; His Interviews with Presidents Lincoln and Johnson; His
      Appointment by Gen. Grant to Accompany the Santo Domingo Commission&amp;#x2014;Also to a Seat
      in the Council of the District of Columbia; His Appointment as United States Marshal by
      President R. B. Hayes; Also His Appointment to Be Recorder of Deeds in Washington by President
      J. A. Garfield; with Many Other Interesting and Important Events of His Most Eventful Life;
      With an Introduction by Mr. George L. Ruffin, of Boston</title>
    <date>1892</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-douglasslife-douglass.xml</filename>
    <author>Frederick Douglass</author>
    <title>Life and Times of Frederick Douglass: His Early Life as a Slave, His Escape from Bondage,
      and His Complete History to the Present Time</title>
    <date>1881</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-floyd-floyd.xml</filename>
    <author>Silas Xavier Floyd</author>
    <title>Life of Charles T. Walker, D.D., (&quot;The Black Spurgeon.&quot;) Pastor Mt. Olivet
      Baptist Church, New York City</title>
    <date>1902</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-henryg-henryg.xml</filename>
    <author>George Henry</author>
    <title>Life of George Henry. Together with a Brief History of the Colored People in
      America</title>
    <date>1894</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-hortonlife-horton.xml</filename>
    <author>George Moses Horton</author>
    <title>Life of George M. Horton. The Colored Bard of North Carolina from &quot;The Poetical
      Works of George M. Horton, the Colored Bard of North Carolina, to which is Prefixed the Life
      of the Author, written by himself.&quot;</title>
    <date>1845</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-mason-mason.xml</filename>
    <author>Isaac Mason</author>
    <title>Life of Isaac Mason as a Slave</title>
    <date>1893</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-mars-mars.xml</filename>
    <author>James Mars</author>
    <title>Life of James Mars, a Slave Born and Sold in Connecticut. Written by Himself</title>
    <date> 1868</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-mars64-mars64.xml</filename>
    <author>James Mars</author>
    <title>Life of James Mars, A Slave Born and Sold in Connecticut. Written by Himself</title>
    <date>1864</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-thompson-thompson.xml</filename>
    <author>John Thompson</author>
    <title>The Life of John Thompson, a Fugitive Slave; Containing His History of 25 Years in
      Bondage, and His Providential Escape. Written by Himself</title>
    <date>1856</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-heth-heth.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>The Life of Joice Heth, the Nurse of Gen. George Washington, (the Father of Our Country,)
      Now Living at the Astonishing Age of 161 Years, and Weighs Only 46 Pounds</title>
    <date>1835</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-henson49-henson49.xml</filename>
    <author>Josiah Henson</author>
    <title>The Life of Josiah Henson, Formerly a Slave, Now an Inhabitant of Canada, as Narrated by
      Himself</title>
    <date>1849</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-mccray-mary.xml</filename>
    <author>S. J. McCray</author>
    <title>Life of Mary F. McCray: Born and Raised a Slave in the State of Kentucky</title>
    <date>1898</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jasper-jasper.xml</filename>
    <author>Edwin Archer Randolph</author>
    <title>The Life of Rev. John Jasper, Pastor of Sixth Mt. Zion Baptist Church, Richmond, Va.,
      from His Birth to the Present Time, with His Theory on the Rotation of the Sun</title>
    <date>1884</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-andersonr-andersonr.xml</filename>
    <author>Robert Anderson</author>
    <title>The Life of Rev. Robert Anderson. Born the 22d Day of February, in the Year of Our Lord
      1819, and Joined the Methodist Episcopal Church in 1839. This Book Shall Be Called The Young
      Men&apos;s Guide, Or, the Brother in White</title>
    <date>1892</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jamesth-jamesth.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas James</author>
    <title>Life of Rev. Thomas James, by Himself</title>
    <date>1886</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-greena-greena.xml</filename>
    <author>A. R. Green</author>
    <title>The Life of the Rev. Dandridge F. Davis, of the African M. E. Church. With a Brief
      Account of His Conversion and Ministerial Labors, from August 1834, till March 1847. Also, a
      Brief Sketch of the Life of the Rev. David Conyou, of the A. M. E. C. and His Ministerial
      Labors. To Which Is Annexed the Funeral Discourse Delivered at the Ohio Conference, in
      Zanesville, on the Decease of the Rev. D. F. Davis, by the Author</title>
    <date>1850</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-greenew-greenew.xml</filename>
    <author>Elisha Winfield Green</author>
    <title>Life of the Rev. Elisha W. Green, One of the Founders of the Kentucky Normal and
      Theological Institute--Now the State University at Louisville; Eleven Years Moderator of the
      Mt. Zion Baptist Association; Five Years Moderator of the Consolidated Baptist Educational
      Association and Over Thirty Years Pastor of the Colored Baptist Churches of Maysville and
      Paris. Written by Himself.</title>
    <date>1888</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-beardj-beard.xml</filename>
    <author>J. R. Beard</author>
    <title>The Life of Toussaint L&apos;Ouverture, the Negro Patriot of Hayti: Comprising an Account
      of the Struggle for Liberty in the Island, and a Sketch of Its History to the Present
      Period</title>
    <date> 1853</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-grimes55-grimes55.xml</filename>
    <author>William Grimes</author>
    <title>Life of William Grimes, the Runaway Slave, Brought Down to the Present Time.</title>
    <date>1855</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-grimes25-grimes25.xml</filename>
    <author>William Grimes</author>
    <title>Life of William Grimes, the Runaway Slave. Written by Himself</title>
    <date>1825</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-lowery-lowery.xml</filename>
    <author>I. E. Lowery</author>
    <title>Life on the Old Plantation in Ante-Bellum Days, or, A Story Based on Facts</title>
    <date>1911</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-arthur-arthur.xml</filename>
    <author> Arthur</author>
    <title>The Life, and Dying Speech of Arthur, a Negro Man; Who Was Executed at Worcester, October
      10, 1768. For a Rape Committed on the Body of One Deborah Metcalfe</title>
    <date>1768</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-allen-allen.xml</filename>
    <author>Richard Allen</author>
    <title>The Life, Experience, and Gospel Labours of the Rt. Rev. Richard Allen. To Which is
      Annexed the Rise and Progress of the African Methodist Episcopal Church in the United States
      of America. Containing a Narrative of the Yellow Fever in the Year of Our Lord 1793: With an
      Address to the People of Colour in the United States</title>
    <date>1833</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jeajohn-jeajohn.xml</filename>
    <author>John Jea</author>
    <title>The Life, History, and Unparalleled Sufferings of John Jea, the African Preacher.
      Compiled and Written by Himself</title>
    <date>1811</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-garlick-garlick.xml</filename>
    <author>Charles A. Garlick</author>
    <title>Life, Including His Escape and Struggle for Liberty of Charles A. Garlick, Born a Slave
      in Old Virginia, Who Secured His Freedom by Running Away from His Master&apos;s Farm in
      1843.</title>
    <date>1902</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-lewisjw-lewisjw.xml</filename>
    <author>John W. Lewis</author>
    <title>The Life, Labors, and Travels of Elder Charles Bowles, of the Free Will Baptist
      Denomination, by Eld. John W. Lewis. Together with an Essay on the Character and Condition of
      the African Race by the Same. Also, an Essay on the Fugitive Law of the U. S. Congress of
      1850, by Rev. Arthur Dearing</title>
    <date>1852</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-smithste-smithste.xml</filename>
    <author>Stephen Smith</author>
    <title>Life, Last Words and Dying Speech of Stephen Smith, a Black Man, Who Was Executed at
      Boston This Day Being Thursday, October 12, 1797 for Burglary</title>
    <date>1797</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-aaron-aaron.xml</filename>
    <author> Aaron</author>
    <title>The Light and Truth of Slavery. Aaron&apos;s History</title>
    <date>1845</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-peterson-peterson.xml</filename>
    <author>Daniel H. Peterson</author>
    <title>The Looking-Glass: Being a True Report and Narrative of the Life, Travels, and Labors of
      the Rev. Daniel H. Peterson, a Colored Clergyman; Embracing a Period of Time from the Year
      1812 to 1854, and Including His Visit to Western Africa</title>
    <date>1854</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-wickham-wickham.xml</filename>
    <author> E. M. W.</author>
    <title>A Lost Family Found; An Authentic Narrative of Cyrus Branch and His Family, Alias John
      White</title>
    <date>1869</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-picquet-picquet.xml</filename>
    <author>Louisa Picquet</author>
    <title>Louisa Picquet, the Octoroon, or, Inside Views of Southern Domestic Life</title>
    <date>1861</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-hawkins-hawkins.xml</filename>
    <author>William G. Hawkins</author>
    <title>Lunsford Lane; or, Another Helper from North Carolina</title>
    <date>1863</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-wheatley-wheatley.xml</filename>
    <author>Phillis Wheatley</author>
    <title>Memoir and Poems of Phillis Wheatley, a Native African and a Slave. Dedicated to the
      Friends of the Africans</title>
    <date> 1834</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brownrw-brownrw.xml</filename>
    <author>Rebecca Warren Brown</author>
    <title>Memoir of Mrs. Chloe Spear, a Native of Africa, Who was Enslaved in Childhood, and Died
      in Boston, January 3, 1815...Aged 65 Years. By a Lady of Boston</title>
    <date> 1832</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-eliza1-eliza1.xml</filename>
    <author> Elizabeth</author>
    <title>Memoir of Old Elizabeth, a Coloured Woman.</title>
    <date> 1863</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-thatcher-thatcher.xml</filename>
    <author>B. B. Thatcher</author>
    <title>Memoir of Phillis Wheatley, a Native African and a Slave</title>
    <date>1834</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-leehf-leehf.xml</filename>
    <author>Hannah Farnham Sawyer Lee</author>
    <title>Memoir of Pierre Toussaint, Born a Slave in St. Domingo</title>
    <date>1854</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-allinson-allinson.xml</filename>
    <author>William J. Allinson</author>
    <title>Memoir of Quamino Buccau, a Pious Methodist</title>
    <date>1851</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-eldridge-eldridge.xml</filename>
    <author>Frances H. Green</author>
    <title>Memoirs of Elleanor Eldridge</title>
    <date>1838</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-levering-levering.xml</filename>
    <author>Sarah R. Levering</author>
    <title>Memoirs of Margaret Jane Blake of Baltimore, Md.: and Selections in Prose and
      Verse</title>
    <date> 1897</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-clement-clement.xml</filename>
    <author>Samuel Spottford Clement</author>
    <title>Memoirs of Samuel Spottford Clement Relating Interesting Experiences in Days of Slavery
      and Freedom</title>
    <date>1908</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-norris-norris.xml</filename>
    <author>Robert Norris</author>
    <title>Memoirs of the Reign of Bossa Ahadee, King of Dahomy, an Inland Country of Guiney. To
      Which Are Added, the Author&apos;s Journey to Abomey, the Capital; and a Short Account of the
      African Slave Trade</title>
    <date>1789</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-burton-burton.xml</filename>
    <author>Annie L. Burton</author>
    <title>Memories of Childhood&apos;s Slavery Days</title>
    <date>1909</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-simmons-simmons.xml</filename>
    <author>William J. Simmons</author>
    <title>Men of Mark: Eminent, Progressive and Rising</title>
    <date>1887</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-bragg-bragg.xml</filename>
    <author>George F. Bragg</author>
    <title>Men of Maryland</title>
    <date>1914</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-mitchell-mitchell.xml</filename>
    <author>Joseph Mitchell</author>
    <title>The Missionary Pioneer, or A Brief Memoir of the Life, Labours, and Death of John
      Stewart, (Man of Colour,) Founder, under God of the Mission among the Wyandotts at Upper
      Sandusky, Ohio</title>
    <date>1827</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-douglass55-douglass55.xml</filename>
    <author>Frederick Douglass</author>
    <title>My Bondage and My Freedom. Part I. Life as a Slave. Part II. Life as a Freeman</title>
    <date>1855</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-washeducation-washing.xml</filename>
    <author>Booker T. Washington</author>
    <title>My Larger Education: Being Chapters from My Experience</title>
    <date>1911</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-branham-branham.xml</filename>
    <author>Levi Branham</author>
    <title>My Life and Travels</title>
    <date>1929</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-walters-walters.xml</filename>
    <author>Alexander Walters</author>
    <title>My Life and Work</title>
    <date>1917</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-stroyer85-stroyer85.xml</filename>
    <author>Jacob Stroyer</author>
    <title>My Life in the South</title>
    <date>1885</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brownsn-brownsn.xml</filename>
    <author>Sterling N. Brown</author>
    <title>My Own Life Story</title>
    <date>1924</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brown80-brown80.xml</filename>
    <author>William Wells Brown</author>
    <title>My Southern Home: or, The South and Its People</title>
    <date>1880</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jacksona-jacksona.xml</filename>
    <author>Andrew Jackson</author>
    <title>Narrative and Writings of Andrew Jackson, of Kentucky; Containing an Account of His
      Birth, and Twenty-Six Years of His Life While a Slave; His Escape; Five Years of Freedom,
      Together with Anecdotes Relating to Slavery; Journal of One Year&apos;s Travels; Sketches,
      etc. Narrated by Himself; Written by a Friend</title>
    <date>1847</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-griswold-griswold.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>A Narrative of &quot;Griswold,&quot; the African Youth, from the Mission School, at Cape
      Palmas, Who Died in Boston, May 16, 1844</title>
    <date>1845</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-veney-veney.xml</filename>
    <author>Bethany Veney</author>
    <title>The Narrative of Bethany Veney: A Slave Woman</title>
    <date>1889</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-cox-cox.xml</filename>
    <author>Mary L. Cox</author>
    <title>Narrative of Dimmock Charlton, a British Subject, Taken from the Brig &quot;Peacock&quot;
      by the U.S. Sloop &quot;Hornet,&quot; Enslaved while a Prisoner of War, and Retained
      Forty-Five Years in Bondage</title>
    <date>1859</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-greenw-greenw.xml</filename>
    <author>William Green</author>
    <title>Narrative of Events in the Life of William Green, (Formerly a Slave.) Written by
      Himself.</title>
    <date>1853</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-penning-penning.xml</filename>
    <author>James W. C. Pennington</author>
    <title>A Narrative of Events of the Life of J. H. Banks, an Escaped Slave, from the Cotton
      State, Alabama, in America</title>
    <date>1861</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-williamsjames-williams.xml</filename>
    <author>James Williams</author>
    <title>A Narrative of Events Since the First of August, 1834, By James Williams, an Apprenticed
      Labourer in Jamaica</title>
    <date>1837</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-boxbrown-boxbrown.xml</filename>
    <author>Henry Box Brown</author>
    <title>Narrative of Henry Box Brown, Who Escaped from Slavery, Enclosed in a Box 3 Feet Long and
      2 Wide. Written from a Statement of Facts Made by Himself. With Remarks Upon the Remedy for
      Slavery. By Charles Stearns</title>
    <date>1849</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-watson-watson.xml</filename>
    <author>Henry Watson</author>
    <title>Narrative of Henry Watson, a Fugitive Slave</title>
    <date> 1848</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-curry-curry.xml</filename>
    <author>James Curry</author>
    <title>Narrative of James Curry, A Fugitive Slave</title>
    <date>1840</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-roberts-roberts.xml</filename>
    <author>James Roberts</author>
    <title>The Narrative of James Roberts, a Soldier Under Gen. Washington in the Revolutionary War,
      and Under Gen. Jackson at the Battle of New Orleans, in the War of 1812: &quot;a Battle Which
      Cost Me a Limb, Some Blood, and Almost My Life&quot;</title>
    <date>1858</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-williams-williams.xml</filename>
    <author>James Williams</author>
    <title>Narrative of James Williams, an American Slave, Who Was for Several Years a Driver on a
      Cotton Plantation in Alabama</title>
    <date>1838</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-stedman-stedman.xml</filename>
    <author>John Gabriel Stedman</author>
    <title>Narrative of Joanna; An Emancipated Slave, of Surinam. (From Stedman&apos;s Narrative of
      a Five Year&apos;s Expedition Against the Revolted Negroes of Surinam)</title>
    <date>1838</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-lanelunsford-lane.xml</filename>
    <author>Lunsford Lane</author>
    <title>The Narrative of Lunsford Lane, Formerly of Raleigh, N.C. Embracing an Account of His
      Early Life, the Redemption by Purchase of Himself and Family from Slavery, and His Banishment
      from the Place of His Birth for the Crime of Wearing a Colored Skin. Published by
      Himself</title>
    <date>1842</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-upham-upham.xml</filename>
    <author>T. C. Upham</author>
    <title>Narrative of Phebe Ann Jacobs</title>
    <date>1850</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-truth50-truth50.xml</filename>
    <author>Sojourner Truth</author>
    <title>Narrative of Sojourner Truth, a Northern Slave, Emancipated from Bodily Servitude by the
      State of New York, in 1828</title>
    <date>1850</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-truth75-truth75.xml</filename>
    <author>Sojourner Truth</author>
    <title>Narrative of Sojourner Truth; a Bondswoman of Olden Time, Emancipated by the New York
      Legislature in the Early Part of the Present Century; with a History of Her Labors and
      Correspondence, Drawn from Her &quot;Book of Life&quot;</title>
    <date>1875</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-truth84-truth84.xml</filename>
    <author>Sojourner Truth</author>
    <title>Narrative of Sojourner Truth; a Bondswoman of Olden Time, Emancipated by the New York
      Legislature in the Early Part of the Present Century; with a History of Her Labors and
      Correspondence Drawn from Her &quot;Book of Life;&quot; Also, a Memorial Chapter, Giving the
      Particulars of Her Last Sickness and Death.</title>
    <date>1884</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-bayley-bayley.xml</filename>
    <author>Solomon Bayley</author>
    <title>A Narrative of Some Remarkable Incidents in the Life of Solomon Bayley, Formerly a Slave
      in the State of Delaware, North America; Written by Himself, and Published for His Benefit; to
      Which Are Prefixed, a Few Remarks by Robert Hurnard</title>
    <date>1825</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-roper-roper.xml</filename>
    <author>Moses Roper</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Adventures and Escape of Moses Roper, from American Slavery. With an
      Appendix, Containing a List of Places Visited by the Author in Great Britain and Ireland and
      the British Isles; and Other Matter</title>
    <date>1848</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-roper-roper.xml</filename>
    <author>Moses Roper</author>
    <title>A Narrative of the Adventures and Escape of Moses Roper, from American Slavery</title>
    <date>1838</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-cugoano-cugoano.xml</filename>
    <author>Ottobah Cugoano</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Enslavement of Ottobah Cugoano, a Native of Africa; Published by Himself
      in the Year 1787. In &quot;The Negro&apos;s Memorial; or, Abolitionist&apos;s Catechism; by an
      Abolitionist&quot; (pp. 120-127), by [Fisher, Thomas] 1781?-1836</title>
    <date> 1825</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-bibb-bibb.xml</filename>
    <author>Henry Bibb</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Life and Adventures of Henry Bibb, an American Slave, Written by
      Himself</title>
    <date> 1849</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-venture2-venture2.xml</filename>
    <author>Venture Smith</author>
    <title>A Narrative of the Life and Adventures of Venture, a Native of Africa, but Resident Above
      Sixty Years in the United States of America. Related by Himself. New London: Printed in 1798.
      Reprinted A. D. 1835, and Published by a Descendant of Venture. Revised and Republished with
      Traditions by H. M. Selden, Haddam, Conn., 1896</title>
    <date>1897</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-venture-venture.xml</filename>
    <author>Venture Smith</author>
    <title>A Narrative of the Life and Adventures of Venture, a Native of Africa: But Resident above
      Sixty Years in the United States of America. Related by Himself</title>
    <date>1798</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-offley-offley.xml</filename>
    <author>G. W. Offley</author>
    <title>A Narrative of the Life and Labors of the Rev. G. W. Offley, a Colored Man, Local
      Preacher and Missionary; Who Lived Twenty-Seven Years at the South and Twenty-Three at the
      North; Who Never Went to School a Day in His Life, and Only Commenced to Learn His Letters
      When Nineteen Years and Eight Months Old; the Emancipation of His Mother and Her Three
      Children; How He Learned to Read While Living in a Slave State, and Supported Himself from the
      Time He Was Nine Years Old Until He Was Twenty-One</title>
    <date> 1859</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-douglass-douglass.xml</filename>
    <author>Frederick Douglass</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Life of Frederick Douglass, an American Slave. Written by
      Himself</title>
    <date>1845</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brownbox-brownbox.xml</filename>
    <author>Henry Box Brown</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Life of Henry Box Brown, Written by Himself</title>
    <date> 1851</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-greenjd-greenjd.xml</filename>
    <author>J. D. Green</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Life of J. D. Green, a Runaway Slave, from Kentucky, Containing an
      Account of His Three Escapes, in 1839, 1846, and 1848</title>
    <date>1864</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-watkin52-watkin52.xml</filename>
    <author>James Watkins</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Life of James Watkins, Formerly a &quot;Chattel&quot; in Maryland, U.
      S.; Containing an Account of His Escape from Slavery, Together with an Appeal on Behalf of
      Three Millions of Such &quot;Pieces of Property,&quot; Still Held Under the Standard of the
      Eagle</title>
    <date>1852</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-adams-adams.xml</filename>
    <author>John Quincy Adams</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Life of John Quincy Adams, When in Slavery, and Now as a Freeman</title>
    <date>1872</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-grandy-grandy.xml</filename>
    <author>Moses Grandy</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Life of Moses Grandy, Late a Slave in the United States of
      America</title>
    <date>1843</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-davisn-davis.xml</filename>
    <author>Noah Davis</author>
    <title>A Narrative of the Life of Rev. Noah Davis, a Colored Man. Written by Himself, at the Age
      of Fifty-Four</title>
    <date> 1859</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-hopper-hopper.xml</filename>
    <author>Isaac T. Hopper</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Life of Thomas Cooper</title>
    <date>1832</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-gronniosaw-gronnios.xml</filename>
    <author>James Albert Ukawsaw Gronniosaw</author>
    <title>A Narrative of the Most Remarkable Particulars in the Life of James Albert Ukawsaw
      Gronniosaw, an African Prince, as Related by Himself</title>
    <date>1770</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-pendleton-pendle.xml</filename>
    <author>Leila Amos Pendleton</author>
    <title>A Narrative of the Negro</title>
    <date>1912</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-clarke-clarke.xml</filename>
    <author>Lewis Garrard Clarke</author>
    <title>Narrative of the Sufferings of Lewis Clarke, During a Captivity of More than Twenty-Five
      Years, Among the Algerines of Kentucky, One of the So Called Christian States of North
      America</title>
    <date> 1845</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-hammon-hammon.xml</filename>
    <author>Briton Hammon</author>
    <title>A Narrative of the Uncommon Sufferings, and Surprizing Deliverance of Briton Hammon, a
      Negro Man,--Servant to General Winslow, of Marshfield, in New-England; Who Returned to Boston,
      After Having Been Absent Almost Thirteen Years. Containing an Account of the Many Hardships He
      Underwent from the Time He Left His Master&apos;s House, in the Year 1747, to the Time of His
      Return to Boston.--How He Was Cast Away in the Capes of Florida;---The Horrid Cruelty and
      Inhuman Barbarity of the Indians in Murdering the Whole Ship&apos;s Crew;---The Manner of His
      Being Carry&apos;d by Them Into Captivity. Also, an Account of His Being Confined Four Years
      and Seven Months in a Close Dungeon,---and the Remarkable Manner in Which He Met with His Good
      Old Master in London; Who Returned to New-England, a Passenger in the Same Ship</title>
    <date>1760</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-smallwood-smallwood.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas Smallwood</author>
    <title>A Narrative of Thomas Smallwood, (Coloured Man:) Giving an Account of His Birth--The
      Period He Was Held in Slavery--His Release--and Removal to Canada, etc. Together With an
      Account of the Underground Railroad. Written by Himself</title>
    <date>1851</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-hayden-hayden.xml</filename>
    <author>William Hayden</author>
    <title>Narrative of William Hayden, Containing a Faithful Account of His Travels for a Number of
      Years, Whilst a Slave, in the South. Written by Himself</title>
    <date>1846</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brown47-brown47.xml</filename>
    <author>William Wells Brown</author>
    <title>Narrative of William W. Brown, a Fugitive Slave. Written by Himself</title>
    <date>1847</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-brownw-brown.xml</filename>
    <author>William Wells Brown</author>
    <title>Narrative of William W. Brown, an American Slave. Written by Himself</title>
    <date>1849</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-mott-mott.xml</filename>
    <author>Abigail Mott</author>
    <title>Narratives of Colored Americans</title>
    <date>1875</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-clarkes-clarkes.xml</filename>
    <author>Lewis Garrard Clarke</author>
    <title>Narratives of the Sufferings of Lewis and Milton Clarke, Sons of a Soldier of the
      Revolution, During a Captivity of More than Twenty Years Among the Slaveholders of Kentucky,
      One of the So-Called Christian States of North America</title>
    <date> 1846</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-warner-warner.xml</filename>
    <author>Ashton Warner</author>
    <title>Negro Slavery Described by a Negro: Being the Narrative of Ashton Warner, a Native of St.
      Vincent&apos;s. With an Appendix Containing the Testimony of Four Christian Ministers,
      Recently Returned from the Colonies, on the System of Slavery as It Now Exists</title>
    <date>1831</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-bruce-bruce.xml</filename>
    <author>Henry Clay Bruce</author>
    <title>The New Man: Twenty-Nine Years a Slave,Twenty-Nine Years a Free Man</title>
    <date>1895</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-drew-drew.xml</filename>
    <author>Benjamin Drew</author>
    <title>A North-Side View of Slavery. The Refugee: or the Narratives of Fugitive Slaves in
      Canada. Related by Themselves, with an Account of the History and Condition of the Colored
      Population of Upper Canada</title>
    <date>1856</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-holley-holley.xml</filename>
    <author>J. W. Holley</author>
    <title>The Old Faithful Servant: Life History of J.W. Holley: Born and Reared a Slave: After
      Freedom Became a Worker in the Master&apos;s Vineyard</title>
    <date>1924</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-mallory-mallory.xml</filename>
    <author>W. Mallory</author>
    <title>Old Plantation Days</title>
    <date>1902</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-lewisj-lewisj.xml</filename>
    <author>J. Vance Lewis</author>
    <title>Out of the Ditch. A True Story of an Ex-Slave</title>
    <date>1910</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-fleming-fleming.xml</filename>
    <author>Walter L. Fleming</author>
    <title>&quot;Pap&quot; Singleton, The Moses of the Colored Exodus</title>
    <date>1909</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jeter-jeter.xml</filename>
    <author>Henry N. Jeter</author>
    <title>Pastor Henry N. Jeter&apos;s Twenty-five Years Experience with the Shiloh Baptist Church
      and Her History. Corner School and Mary Streets, Newport, R. I.</title>
    <date>1901</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-long-long.xml</filename>
    <author>John Dixon Long</author>
    <title>Pictures of Slavery in Church and State; Including Personal Reminiscences, Biographical
      Sketches, Anecdotes, etc. etc. with an Appendix, Containing the Views of John Wesley and
      Richard Watson on Slavery</title>
    <date>1857</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-manzano-manzano.xml</filename>
    <author>Juan Francisco Manzano</author>
    <title>Poems by a Slave in the Island of Cuba, Recently Liberated; Translated from the Spanish,
      by R. R. Madden, M.D. With the History of the Early Life of the Negro Poet, Written by
      Himself; to Which Are Prefixed Two Pieces Descriptive of Cuban Slavery and the Slave-Traffic,
      by R. R. M.</title>
    <date>1840</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-hortonpoem-hortonpoem.xml</filename>
    <author>George Moses Horton</author>
    <title>The Poetical Works of George M. Horton: The Colored Bard of North Carolina: To Which is
      Prefixed the Life of the Author, Written by Himself</title>
    <date>1845</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-bruceje-bruceje.xml</filename>
    <author>John Edward Bruce</author>
    <title>Prince Hall, the Pioneer of Negro Masonry. Proofs of the Legitimacy of Prince Hall
      Masonry</title>
    <date>1921</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-singleton-singleton.xml</filename>
    <author>William Henry Singleton</author>
    <title>Recollections of My Slavery Days</title>
    <date> 1922</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-runaway-runaway.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>Recollections of Slavery by a Runaway Slave</title>
    <date>1838</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-parker-parker.xml</filename>
    <author>Allen Parker</author>
    <title>Recollections of Slavery Times</title>
    <date> 1895</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-straker-straker.xml</filename>
    <author>D. Augustus Straker</author>
    <title>Reflections on the Life and Times of Toussaint L&apos;Overture, the Negro Haytien,
      Commander-in-Chief of the Army, Ruler under the Dominion of France, and Author of The
      Independence of Hayti</title>
    <date>1886</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-capehart-capehart.xml</filename>
    <author>L. C. Capehart</author>
    <title>Reminiscences of Isaac and Sukey, Slaves of B. F. Moore, of Raleigh, N.C.</title>
    <date>1907</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-taylorsu-taylorsu.xml</filename>
    <author>Susie King Taylor</author>
    <title>Reminiscences of My Life in Camp with the 33d United States Colored Troops Late 1st S. C.
      Volunteers</title>
    <date> 1902</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jacksonc-jackson.xml</filename>
    <author>Fanny Jackson Coppin</author>
    <title>Reminiscences of School Life, and Hints on Teaching</title>
    <date>1913</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-captain-captain.xml</filename>
    <author>Charles Stuart</author>
    <title>Reuben Maddison: A True Story</title>
    <date>1835</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-loguen-loguen.xml</filename>
    <author>J. W. Loguen</author>
    <title>The Rev. J. W. Loguen, as a Slave and as a Freeman. A Narrative of Real Life</title>
    <date> 1859</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-bragg1915-bragg1915.xml</filename>
    <author>George F. Bragg</author>
    <title>Richard Allen and Absalom Jones, by the Rev. George F. Bragg, in Honor of the Centennial
      of the African Methodist Episcopal Church, Which Occurs in the Year 1916</title>
    <date>1915</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-royal-royal.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>The Royal African: or, Memoirs of the Young Prince of Annamaboe. Comprehending a Distinct
      Account of His Country and Family; His Elder Brother&apos;s Voyage to France, and Reception
      there; the Manner in Which Himself Was Confided by His Father to the Captain Who Sold Him; His
      Condition While a Slave in Barbadoes; the True Cause of His Bring Redeemed; His Voyage from
      Thence; and Reception Here in England. Interspers&apos;d Throughout with Several Historical
      Remarks on the Commerce of the European Nations, Whose Subjects Frequent the Coast of Guinea.
      To which is Prefixed a Letter from the Author to a Person of Distinction, in Reference to Some
      Natural Curiosities in Africa; as Well as Explaining the Motives which Induced Him to Compose
      These Memoirs.</title>
    <date>1750</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-craft-craft.xml</filename>
    <author>William Craft</author>
    <title>Running a Thousand Miles for Freedom; or, the Escape of William and Ellen Craft from
      Slavery</title>
    <date>1860</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-hall-hall.xml</filename>
    <author>Samuel Hall</author>
    <title>Samuel Hall, 47 Years a Slave; A Brief Story of His Life Before and After Freedom Came to
      Him</title>
    <date>1912</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-maysamuel-maysamuel.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>Samuel Joseph May. Born in Boston, Massachusetts, September 12th, 1797. Died in Syracuse,
      New York, July 1st, 1871</title>
    <date>1871</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-bradford-bradford.xml</filename>
    <author>Sarah H. Bradford</author>
    <title>Scenes in the Life of Harriet Tubman</title>
    <date>1869</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-suggs-suggs.xml</filename>
    <author>Eliza Suggs</author>
    <title>Shadow and Sunshine</title>
    <date>1906</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-mcpherson-mcpherson.xml</filename>
    <author>Christopher McPherson</author>
    <title>A Short History of the Life of Christopher McPherson, Alias Pherson, Son of Christ, King
      of Kings and Lord of Lords. Containing a Collection of Certificates, Letters, &amp;amp;c.
      Written by Himself</title>
    <date>1855</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-franklin-franklin.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>A Sketch of Henry Franklin and Family.</title>
    <date>1887</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-charlton-charlton.xml</filename>
    <author>Lewis Charlton</author>
    <title>Sketch of the Life of Mr. Lewis Charlton, and Reminiscences of Slavery</title>
    <date/>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-tubbee-tubbee.xml</filename>
    <author>Okah Tubbee</author>
    <title>A Sketch of the Life of Okah Tubbee, (Called) William Chubbee, Son of the Head Chief,
      Mosholeh Tubbee, of the Choctaw Nation of Indians</title>
    <date>1852</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-gurley-gurley.xml</filename>
    <author>Ralph Randolph Gurley</author>
    <title>Sketch of the Life of the Rev. Lott Cary in &quot;Life of Jehudi Ashmun, Late Colonial
      Agent in Liberia. With An Appendix, Containing Extracts from his Journal and Other Writings;
      With a Brief Sketch of the Life of the Rev. Lott Cary&quot;</title>
    <date> 1835</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-bethune-bethune.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>A Sketch of the Life of Thomas Greene Bethune (Blind Tom)</title>
    <date>1865</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-stroyer-stroyer.xml</filename>
    <author>Jacob Stroyer</author>
    <title>Sketches of My Life in the South. Part I</title>
    <date>1879</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-randol55-randol55.xml</filename>
    <author>Peter Randolph</author>
    <title>Sketches of Slave Life: Or, Illustrations of the &quot;Peculiar Institution&quot; </title>
    <date>1855</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-thompson1-thompson.xml</filename>
    <author>Mary W. Thompson</author>
    <title>Sketches of the History, Character, and Dying Testimony, of Beneficiaries of the Colored
      Home, in the City of New-York</title>
    <date>1851</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-mountain-mountain.xml</filename>
    <author>Joseph Mountain</author>
    <title>Sketches of the Life of Joseph Mountain, a Negro, Who Was Executed at New-Haven, on the
      20th Day of October, 1790, for a Rape, Committed on the 26th Day of May Last. [The Writer of
      This History Has Directed That the Money Arising From the Sales Thereof, After Deducting the
      Expence of Printing, &amp;amp;c. Be Given to the Unhappy Girl, Whose Life Is Rendered Wretched
      by the Crime of the Malefactor.]</title>
    <date>1790</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-drumgoold-drumgoold.xml</filename>
    <author>Kate Drumgoold</author>
    <title>A Slave Girl&apos;s Story. Being an Autobiography of Kate Drumgoold</title>
    <date>1898</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jbrown-jbrown.xml</filename>
    <author>John Brown</author>
    <title>Slave Life in Georgia: A Narrative of the Life, Sufferings, and Escape of John Brown, a
      Fugitive Slave, Now in England</title>
    <date>1855</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-fedric-fedric.xml</filename>
    <author>Francis Fedric</author>
    <title>Slave Life in Virginia and Kentucky; or, Fifty Years of Slavery in the Southern States of
      America</title>
    <date> 1863</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-bruner-bruner.xml</filename>
    <author>Peter Bruner</author>
    <title>A Slave&apos;s Adventures Toward Freedom. Not Fiction, but the True Story of a
      Struggle</title>
    <date>1918</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-johnson-johnson.xml</filename>
    <author>Isaac Johnson</author>
    <title>Slavery Days in Old Kentucky. A True Story of a Father Who Sold His Wife and Four
      Children. By One of the Children</title>
    <date>1901</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-ballslavery-ball.xml</filename>
    <author>Charles Ball</author>
    <title>Slavery in the United States: A Narrative of the Life and Adventures of Charles Ball, a
      Black Man, Who Lived Forty Years in Maryland, South Carolina and Georgia, as a Slave Under
      Various Masters, and was One Year in the Navy with Commodore Barney, During the Late
      War</title>
    <date>1837</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-bluett-bluett.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas Bluett</author>
    <title>Some Memoirs of the Life of Job, the Son of Solomon, the High Priest of Boonda in Africa;
      Who was a Slave About Two Years in Maryland; and Afterwards Being Brought to England, was Set
      Free, and Sent to His Native Land in the Year 1734</title>
    <date>1734</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-gallaudet-gallaudet.xml</filename>
    <author>T. H. Gallaudet</author>
    <title>A Statement with Regard to the Moorish Prince, Abduhl Rahhahman</title>
    <date>1828</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-eliot-eliot.xml</filename>
    <author>William Greenleaf Eliot</author>
    <title>The Story of Archer Alexander: From Slavery to Freedom, March 30, 1863</title>
    <date>1885</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jacksonm-jackson.xml</filename>
    <author>Mattie J. Jackson</author>
    <title>The Story of Mattie J. Jackson: Her Parentage, Experience of Eighteen Years in Slavery,
      Incidents During the War, Her Escape from Slavery: A True Story</title>
    <date>1866</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-twelvetr-twelvetr.xml</filename>
    <author>Harper Twelvetrees</author>
    <title>The Story of the Life of John Anderson, the Fugitive Slave</title>
    <date>1863</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-watkins-watkins.xml</filename>
    <author>James Watkins</author>
    <title>Struggles for Freedom; or The Life of James Watkins, Formerly a Slave in Maryland, U. S.;
      in Which is Detailed a Graphic Account of His Extraordinary Escape from Slavery, Notices of
      the Fugitive Slave Law, the Sentiments of American Divines on the Subject of Slavery, etc.,
      etc.</title>
    <date>1860</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-iwilliams-iwilliams.xml</filename>
    <author>Isaac D. Williams</author>
    <title>Sunshine and Shadow of Slave Life. Reminiscences as told by Isaac D. Williams to
      &quot;Tege&quot;</title>
    <date>1885</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-hughes-hughes.xml</filename>
    <author>Louis Hughes</author>
    <title>Thirty Years a Slave: From Bondage to Freedom: The Institution of Slavery as Seen on the
      Plantation and in the Home of the Planter</title>
    <date>1897</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-brown52-brown52.xml</filename>
    <author>William Wells Brown</author>
    <title>Three Years in Europe: Or, Places I Have Seen and People I Have Met</title>
    <date>1852</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-detroit-detroit.xml</filename>
    <author> No Author</author>
    <title>A Thrilling Narrative from the Lips of the Sufferers of the Late Detroit Riot, March 6,
      1863, With the Hair Breadth Escapes of Men, Women and Children, and Destruction of Colored
      Men&apos;s Property, Not Less Than $15,000.</title>
    <date>1863</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-tubbee1848-tubbee1848.xml</filename>
    <author>Okah Tubbee</author>
    <title>A Thrilling Sketch of the Life of the Distinguished Chief Okah Tubbee Alias, Wm. Chubbee,
      Son of the Head Chief, Mosholeh Tubbee, of the Choctaw Nation of Indians</title>
    <date>1848</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-beard63-beard63.xml</filename>
    <author>J. R. Beard</author>
    <title>Toussaint L&apos;Ouverture: A Biography and Autobiography</title>
    <date>1863</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-henderson-henderson.xml</filename>
    <author>Madison Henderson</author>
    <title>Trials and Confessions of Madison Henderson, Alias Blanchard, Alfred Amos Warrick, James
      W. Seward, and Charles Brown, Murderers of Jesse Baker and Jacob Weaver, as Given by
      Themselves; and a Likeness of Each, Taken in Jail Shortly after Their Arrest</title>
    <date>1841</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-armistead-armistead.xml</filename>
    <author>Wilson Armistead</author>
    <title>A Tribute for the Negro: Being a Vindication of the Moral, Intellectual, and Religious
      Capabilities of the Colored Portion of Mankind; with Particular Reference to the African
      Race</title>
    <date>1848</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-jjacobs-jjacobs.xml</filename>
    <author>John S. Jacobs</author>
    <title>A True Tale of Slavery. From The Leisure Hour: A Family Journal of Instruction and
      Recreation, February 7, 14, 21, 28, 1861</title>
    <date>1861</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-henson58-henson58.xml</filename>
    <author>Josiah Henson</author>
    <title>Truth Stranger Than Fiction. Father Henson&apos;s Story of His Own Life</title>
    <date>1858</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-northup-northup.xml</filename>
    <author>Solomon Northup</author>
    <title>Twelve Years a Slave: Narrative of Solomon Northup, a Citizen of New-York, Kidnapped in
      Washington City in 1841, and Rescued in 1853</title>
    <date>1853</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-johnson1-johnson.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas L. Johnson</author>
    <title>Twenty-Eight Years a Slave, or The Story of My Life in Three Continents</title>
    <date>1909</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-steward-steward.xml</filename>
    <author>Austin Steward</author>
    <title>Twenty-Two Years a Slave, and Forty Years a Freeman; Embracing a Correspondence of
      Several Years, While President of Wilberforce Colony, London, Canada West</title>
    <date>1857</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-rayemma-rayemma.xml</filename>
    <author>Emma J. Ray</author>
    <title>Twice Sold, Twice Ransomed: Autobiography of Mr. and Mrs. L. P. Ray</title>
    <date>1926</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-foster-foster.xml</filename>
    <author>Gustavus L. Foster</author>
    <title>Uncle Johnson, the Pilgrim of Six Score Years</title>
    <date>1867</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-edwardsj-edwardsj.xml</filename>
    <author>John Passmore Edwards</author>
    <title>Uncle Tom&apos;s Companions: Or, Facts Stranger Than Fiction. A Supplement to Uncle
      Tom&apos;s Cabin: Being Startling Incidents in the Lives of Celebrated Fugitive
      Slaves.</title>
    <date>1852</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-henson-henson.xml</filename>
    <author>Josiah Henson</author>
    <title>Uncle Tom&apos;s Story of His Life. An Autobiography of the Rev. Josiah Henson (Mrs.
      Harriet Beecher Stowe&apos;s &quot;Uncle Tom&quot;). From 1789 to 1876. With a Preface by Mrs.
      Harriet Beecher Stowe, and an Introductory Note by George Sturge, and S. Morley, Esq., M.
      P.</title>
    <date>1876</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-washington-washing.xml</filename>
    <author>Booker T. Washington</author>
    <title>Up from Slavery: An Autobiography</title>
    <date>1901</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>fpn-burtont-burton.xml</filename>
    <author>Thomas William Burton</author>
    <title>What Experience Has Taught Me: An Autobiography of Thomas William Burton</title>
    <date>1910</date>
  </row>
  <row>
    <filename>neh-wilkerson-wilkerson.xml</filename>
    <author>Major James Wilkerson</author>
    <title>Wilkerson&apos;s History of His Travels &amp;amp; Labors, in the United States, As a
      Missionary, in Particular, That of the Union Seminary, Located in Franklin Co., Ohio, Since He
      Purchased His Liberty in New Orleans, La. &amp;amp;c.</title>
    <date>1861</date>
  </row>
</root>
